CRISTO PÉREZ SUÁREZ

Frontend Developer | React • Next.js • Node.js | Creating Modern, Minimalist Apps with Intuitive UX/UI

Las Palmas, Spain • cristobits0101@gmail.com

Summary

2 year of experience with JavaScript through internships and contributions to open-source projects. Completed an IBM Scrum course that strengthened my teamwork, communication and problem-solving skills. Committed to improving user experience and advancing inclusion through insights gained from a Google course.

Experience

Lectores BetaRemoteFront-End DeveloperJun 2024 - Present

- Managed Git flow with Trunk-Based Development.
- Set up the project and dependencies with the frontend architect.
- Planned workflows and technologies in daily meetings.
- Built a high-performance, responsive landing page.
- Improved user experience based on sprint feedback.

Skills: Scrum, HTML, CSS, TypeScript (5.6), React (18.3), Next.js (14.2), JSON, Git (TBD) and GitHub.

Altia Las Palmas, Spain Full-Stack Developer Jan 2024 - May 2024

- Applied Scrum over 8 sprints to deliver features and fix bugs.
- Developed and tested 3 microservices and 1 RESTful API for new features.
- Integrated 1 WebSocket API for real-time communication in the CMS.
- Built 30 custom components and 6 adaptive templates in 2 months.
- Delivered 100% of functionalities on time ensuring steady project progress.
- Scored 10 after 5 months of teamwork and project integration training.

Skills: FreeMarker (2.3), YAML, Bootstrap (5.2), JavaScript (ES6), Java (17/OOP), XML and Magnolia CMS (6.2).

Education

IES El RincónLas Palmas, SpainSenior Technician in Web Application Development (GPA: 8.36).Sep 2022 - Jun 2024

Certifications

UdemyLearning PlatformSpring Framework 6 & Spring Boot 3 (81 hours).Issued Jul 2024

CourseraMOOCIBM IT Scrum Master (93 hours).Issued Dec 2023AWS Cloud Technical Essentials (26 hours).Issued May 2023Meta Full-Stack Engineer (410 hours).Issued Mar 2023Google UX Design (154 hours).Issued Jul 2022

Cisco Networking AcademyNetAcadNetworking Essentials (70 hours).Issued Jun 2022

Languages

- English B1 (I am currently continuing to study English online with native teachers to improve my level).
- Spanish Native.